本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻译   米小勒    Lottie筱妤   小欠    Marshal同学   蔡茸茸
翻译   CS小明漫画家   如是我闻   kiko   Isabelle很内疚
时间轴   羲和     后期   蜡笔小新的眉毛
校对   米小勒      总监   米小勒
僵 尸
国 度
第一季 第一集
.
这是一次全球性警报
This is a worldwide alert.
留守静待重要信息
Standby for important information
封锁疫区
Quarantine.
总统已经死亡
The president is dead.
这是一场事关种族灭绝的大事件
This is an extinction scale event.
切勿慌张
Do not panic.
距离首次病毒爆发已有三年
Three years after the first infection,
国家政府已经沦陷
national governments have fallen.
无任何解药
There is no cure.
朴茨茅斯海军监狱
yzm[疫情控制研究中心]
疫情爆发第二年  5月5日
快
Go!
快走
停火  节省弹药  瓦尔迪兹
Cease fire! Save your ammo, Valdez.
节省弹药
Save your ammo.
国安局紧急指挥中心
三角洲X光小队  这里是北极光阵地
Delta-Xray-Delta. This is Camp Northern Light.
请回话
Come in.
三角洲X光小队  这里是北极光阵地
Delta-Xray-Delta. This is Camp Northern Light.
请回话
Come in.
为何他们还没有撤出去
Why haven't they evacuated?
撤离小队仍在既定路线上
The extraction team is still in route.
他们的初始着陆点已经沦陷
Their initial landing site was overrunning.
我无法再用无线电联系上X光小队
And I can't get anyone from Delta-Xray on the radio.
那就接着试
Well keep trying.
这是新的目的地坐标
Here are the new destination coordinates.
再联系两分钟  之后就靠他们自己的了
Two more minutes and they're on their own.
只要飞机一降落我们立即撤离
We evac as soon as the plane's loaded.
所有东西维持原样
Keep everything hot.
谁晓得
Who knows
可能未来某日我们还会回来呢
We might be back someday.
两分钟后  各位准备撤离
Two minutes. Move it people!
快点赫尔南德斯  撤了  赶紧走
Come on, Hernandez! Out of there! Let's go!
三角洲X光小队
Delta-Xray-Delta.
请回话
Come in.
这里是三角洲X光小队  你是谁
This is Delta-Xray-Delta! Who the hell are you?
这里是西蒙·克劳勒  长官
This is Simon Cruller, sir.
我是美国国安局系统操作员
I'm a Sys Op working for the NSA.
来自北极光阵地
Camp Northern Light.
我这里有中央总部下达的新命令
I have new orders for you from Cent Com.
现在可有点小忙
Little busy right now.
收到  长官
Yes, sir.
我们即将撤退  所以我得马上告诉您
We're about to bug out ourselves so I'll get right to it.
我这里有新目的地的GPS坐标
I have GPS coordinates for your new destination.
是疾控中心大规模感染对策研究所
It's the CDC Mass Infection Lab
在威尔森山上[加州]
on Mount Wilson.
你们需要护送莫奇医生和其他幸存者
You're to escort Doctor Merch and any other survivors
前往该目的地  这是优先级1级的命令
to this location. It's Priority Level One!
喂喂  你确定吗
Hey! Hey! Are you sure?!
目的地在加利福尼亚呢
These coordinates are in California!
收到的命令如此  长官
That's a roger, sir.
我的直升机在哪呢
Where's my chopper?
飞机依旧在往您那里去的路上  长官
I'm showing that it's still inbound sir.
但是不用担心  X光小队  我哪也不会去
But don't you worry, Delta-Xray. I'm not going anywhere.
你得把我们从这鬼地方弄出去  你听到我说的了吗
You get us the hell out of here! You hear me?!
这道门撑不住的
This gate won't hold them.
你尽可能拖住他们
You keep them off as long as you can.
然后你就撤回研究所  明白了吗
Then you fall back to the lab. Okay?
我去撤离其他人  你能做得到
I'll evacuate the others. You can do this.
我们没时间了
We don't have time for this.
我们不能就这么停下
We can't stop yet!
这是我们测试新菌株的最后机会
This is our last chance to test the new strains.
不
No!
他们看上去可不像志愿者啊
They don't look like volunteers to me.
成千上万的人不明原因的死去
Millions of people are dying for no reason.
这些人的死会帮助我们找到疫苗
These men are gonna die to help us find a vaccine.
如果奏效  他们之中就会有人活得比我们都久
If it works, one of them may outlive us all.
说的好听  你自己怎么不来试试
Yeah, well why don't you take it then, huh?
不用担心
Don't worry.
如果不成功  我会确保你们直接成仁的
If it doesn't work out, I'll make sure you don't come back.
我谢谢你哈
Fantastic.
依照紧急事态行政指令第七章节的内容
In accordance with the Emergency Executive Order section seven,
特此通知你们被选为测试者
you are hereby notified that you have been selected
直接接受实验物质的检测
for exposure to an experimental substance.
我们也有权利做选择
We got rights.
我们现在起码还是人类  你知道的
We're still human you know.
如果测试失败
Should the test fail, all efforts will be made
就会联系你的直系亲属
to contact your next of kin.
琳赛·巴顿总统签署
Signed, President Lindsay Barton.
我以为那个贱人已经死了
I thought that bitch was dead!
她死之前已经签署了这份文件
Not when she signed this order.
不  不  不要
No! No! No!
快点  现在就注射
Now! Do it now!
不要啊  不
No! No!
再给你们五分钟时间
Five minutes!
时间一到  全部人撤离
And we're out of here!
救援小组最好马上就到
The evac better get here soon.
我仁慈地结束你的生命
I give you mercy.
该撤退了
Time to go.
他说得没错
He's right.
没时间了  今天的测试就到此为止吧
Outta time. No more testing today.
不要  不要
No! No! No! No!
不  不  不要啊
No! No! No! No! No! No! No! No! No!
是瓦尔迪兹
It's Valdez.
空运WB6队
Air Cav - Whiskey Bravo Six,
这里是北极光
this is Northern Light.
我时刻关注着你们的动向
I have eyes on your approach.
你们就在那些人的正上方  飞得不错
You're right on top of them man. Awesome flying.
三角洲X光小队正在营救幸存者
Delta Xray is bringing out survivors now.
祝你们好运  WB小队
Good luck, Whisky Bravo.
我们要撤离了
We're out the door ourselves.
来生再见了  长官
Catch you in the next life, sir.
北极光  汇报完毕
Northern Light signing off.
你跟我来
You're coming with me.
等等  你们要干什么
Wait! Where are you going?
别留我一个人在这等僵尸
Don't leave me to the zombies man.
别抛下我  别让我变僵尸  混蛋
Don't leave me! Don't let me turn, you bastard!
带我一起走
Pike me!
带上我  不然我变僵尸也不会放过你们
Pike me or I will hunt you down and eat your brains!
他是我们研制疫苗的最后一丝希望
He was our last hope at finding a vaccine.
现在你才是我们唯一的希望
Now you are.
快走
Come on.
医生
Hey doc!
如果两分钟之后我没有赶上来
If I'm not back in two minutes,
你就告诉他们不要等我了
you tell them to leave without me.
不
No!
没错  快走
Yes! Go ahead! Go!
快走啊
Go!
一年后
疫情爆发第3年
上纽约州
*那条美丽的河*
*The beautiful, beautiful river*
*我们与圣人相聚河边*
*Gather with the saints at the river*
*河水从上帝的宝座下流过*
*That flows by the throne of God*
敬娜娜·格里斯沃尔德
To Nana Griswold.
一位真正的幸存者
A true survivor.
现今没有多少祖母能活这么大岁数了
Not many grandmothers left these days.
尤其是像娜娜这样高寿的
Especially as old as Nana was.
她到底多大岁数了
How old was she anyway?
六十三岁
Sixty-three.
真是高寿啊
Wow. That's old.
六十四岁
Sixty-four.
我还没死呢
And I'm not dead yet.
不过  我觉得是时候可以去见上帝了
But I think it's time.
你们都出去吧
You can all go now.
你把她的东西拿来了吗
Do you have her special?
剩下的就交给我吧
I'll take it from here.
准备好了吗  娜娜
Ready, Nana?
废话  我当然准备好了
Hell yes I'm ready.
我已经在这糟糕的世界上活得够久了
I've had enough of this stinkin' world.
索非亚·克里斯蒂娜·格里斯沃尔德
Sofia Christina Griswold.
借助这件圣礼
With this eight sacrament
我将给予你的灵魂永恒的宁静
I commit your soul to eternal peace.
我仁慈地结束你的生命
I give you...mercy.
*那条美丽的河*
*The beautiful beautiful river*
*我们与圣人相聚河边
*Gather with the saints at the river*
河水从上帝的宝座下流过
*That flows by the throne of God*
加内特呼叫沃伦
This is Garnett to Warren.
加内特呼叫沃伦  完毕
Garnett to Warren, over
沃伦收到  怎么了查理
Go for Warren. What's up Charlie?
我在水边了  请求后援
I'm at the water's edge, could use a little backup.
给我两分钟时间
Two minutes.
这是什么
What is it?
我猜这是个求救信号
I guess a distress signal?
你打算怎么处理它
How do you want to handle it?
我关注他们有一段时间了
Been watching them for a while.
目前我看只有两个男人
As far as I can tell it's just two males.
先看看他们什么来路吧
Let's see what they want.
若情况不妙  再打发他们回去
Can always turn them back around.
奶奶的送终会怎么样了
How did Nana's Eighth go?
不错  都是些好人
Very good. Good people.
谢谢帮忙  我只是...
Thanks for doing it. I just...
下不了手了...做过太多次...
can't anymore. Too many...
没事  她准备好上路了
It's okay. She was ready to go.
大家不都一样吗
Hmmm. Aren't we all.
他们来了
Here they come.
这样吧  我过去招呼他们
All right. I'll handle the meet and greet.
你在这里掩护我
You cover me from here.
要是感觉不对头  你直接趴下
Any problems, you hit the ground.
剩下的就交给我来解决
I'll take care of the rest.
就到这吧  先生们
That's far enough, gentlemen.
上报身份  来自何方  所为何事
Identify yourselves and state your business
狙击手小分队已经将你们包围
Team of snipers has you covered
所以别耍什么花样
so no sudden moves.
马克·哈蒙德中尉  来自三角洲部队
Lieutenant Mark Hammond. Delta Force.
我是说  如果三角洲部队还存在的话
Or least I was when there was still a Delta Force.
我效力于临时政府  在执行任务
I'm on a mission from what's left of the government,
需要你们的援助
and I need your help.
什么任务  哪个政府
What mission? For what government?
坦白说  我也不知道
Look, to be honest I don't know
给我下达命令的人是否还在世
if anybody that gave me the order is still alive.
但我确定的是  我必须把此人
I do know it's imperative that I get this person
送到加利福尼亚的医学实验室
to a medical lab in California.
而且要活的
Alive.
意思是我暂时不能开枪了
Well I guess I won't shoot him Yet.
他是谁
Who is he?
什么神医吗
Some kind of doctor?
不能这么说
Not exactly.
他叫摩菲
His name is Murphy.
这个人也许是人类获救的最后希望
And he may just be the last best chance to save humanity.
亲爱的  你好  是我
Hello, baby, it's me.
现在有空陪我聊几句吗
You got time to talk?
拜托  我的小心肝
Come on, sweetie.
对你我当然有时间了  你知道的
I always have time for you. You know that.
我只是想知道
I just wanted to know
这个圣诞节你回不回来
if you're gonna make it home for Christmas
你答应过我回来的
like you promised?
黛西  我还不能确定
Daisy, I just don't know.
这里的工作太忙了
Things are pretty busy up here.
你和你的高度机密们
You and all your top secrets.
就不能给我让出点时间来吗
Can't they give you some time off?
你不来  大家会失望的
Everybody's gonna be so disappointed.
我知道
I know.
我答应你  我很快回家
But I'll get home soon, I promise.
牛仔怎么样了
How's Cowboy?
他很好
He's fine.
他把你的另一双鞋也咬烂了
He chewed up another pair of your shoes.
有时候我觉得他比我还要想念你
Sometimes I think he misses you more than I do.
虽然听起来不太可能
If that's possible.
你看到新闻上关于华盛顿的报导了吗
Hey, did you see that stuff on the news about Washington?
太疯狂了  对吧
That's crazy, huh?
北极光阵地
Northern Light.
这里是威尔森山疾病控制中心
This is CDC Mount Wilson.
北极光阵地
Northern Light.
这里是威尔森山疾病控制中心  请回答
This is CDC Mount Wilson. Over.
威尔森山  北极光阵地收到
Mount Wilson, this is Northern Light. Over.
实验室已经沦陷
The lab has been overrun.
马克已经撤离原有位置
Operation Bite Mark abandoning location.
请汇报三角洲X光小队现在的位置
What is the status of Delta-Xray-Delta? Over.
三角洲X光小队的位置尚未明确
Delta-Xray location currently unknown.
我们三周前就已失联  收到请回答
We lost contact three weeks ago. Over.
请汇报三角洲X光小队的位置
I need the status of Delta-Xray-Delta.
我们需要...
We need to...
新坐标位置...
new coordinates...
威尔森山  没有收到  请重复
Mount Wilson. We did not copy. Repeat.
没有收到信息  请回答
We did not copy. Over.
威尔森山
Mount Wilson.
我们只需要一些供给必需品
All we need are some basic supplies
然后再把我们送到塔潘齐桥
and transportation south as far as the Tappan Zee bridge.
在那边我们会与新队伍会和
We're meeting a new team there, and they can take us
然后他们会带我们去加利福尼亚
the rest of the way to California.
加利福尼亚  路途相当遥远啊
California sure is a hell of a long way.
塔潘齐桥也够远的
The Tappan Zee bridge is a long way.
要不是我束手无策
I wouldn't ask, but it's imperative
也不会跑来求你们帮忙
and I am out of options.
你是怎么找到这里来的
How'd you find out about this place?
在来的路上经过一个监狱
An ex-cop and some others taking shelter in a prison
听里面一个退职警员和几个人说的
twenty clicks up the road said
国民警卫队建立了庇护所
there was some National Guard
建立了一个营地  他们也许能帮到我们
that set up a camp, might be able to help us out.
是前国家警卫队
"Ex" National Guard.
是的  我曾在佐治亚国家警卫队服役过
Yeah, I was with Georgia National Guard.
沃伦就是从密苏里逃出来的
Warren here was evacuated out of Missouri.
但据我所知  我们是这片地区仅剩的幸存者
But as far as I know, we're the only ones left of our unit.
听着  我知道现在指挥系统已完全失效
Look. I know there's no more chain of command,
警卫队  政府都已不复存在
no more Guard, no more government.
只剩下我们这几个人还在执行命令
Just a few of us out there following orders
因为这就是我们的职责
cuz that's what we do.
到现在为止  我已经失去了八个最亲密的战友
I lost eight of the best men I ever served with getting this far.
我收到的命令是把这个人带到加州的实验室
My orders are to take this man to a lab in California,
这就是我所要做的
and that's what I intend to do.
现在
Now.
你们到底要不要帮我
Are you people going to help me or not?
这人他妈的有什么重要
Why is he so goddamn important?
他带有的信息
He has information vital to
对制造抵抗僵尸病毒的疫苗至关重要
the development of a vaccine for the zombie virus.
我能说的就只有这些了
And that's all I can tell you.
您们还想要知道什么
How much more do you need to know?
我和沃伦可以用卡车送你到塔潘齐那边去
Warren and I can take the pickup truck, bring you to the Tappan Zee.
但那之后你就得自己走了
But you'd be on your own after that.
我要求的就只有这么多
That's all I'm asking.
如果不停地赶路
Well if we keep it moving,
今天天黑之前我们就可以回来了
we can get there and back before nightfall.
我可不敢承担失去卡车的风险
I'm not sure we risk the truck.
也不敢失去你们俩
Or you two.
也许我说得还不够清楚
Maybe I haven't been clear.
这件事比你们的卡车重要得多
This is more important than your trucks.
也比任何人的生命都要重要得多
Or anyone's life.
包括我自己的生命
Including my own.
我不想动武逼你们
I don't want to have to insist.
我在两天前就应该已经到集合地点的
I was supposed to meet my rendezvous two days ago.
这件事一定要完成
This needs to happen.
立刻
Now.
听着
Listen.
如果他们想要偷卡车
If they're trying to steal the truck,
做你该做的
do what you got to do.
当然
Always.
保持无线电联络
Stay in radio contact.
如果明天早晨之前还得不到你的消息
We don't hear from you by tomorrow morning,
我们会来找你的
we'll come lookin'.
日落之前他们就能回来了
You'll have them back by sundown.
如果你只想要充足的弹药供给
Well if availability of ammo is all you care about
选这种22号来复枪就没错了
then the 22 is the way to go.
但是  如果你真想让人眼前一亮
But... You really want to make an impression,
就试试这把手枪吧
check out this smoke wagon.
用这个来结果僵尸是最合适的
You really make a z's day with this.
22号来复枪的确能杀死僵尸
Now the 22, that'll kill a z,
但是你得开两三枪
but it's gonna be about two or three shots
才能把它彻底放倒
before the thing's down and dead.
而这个小家伙
This baby?
一枪就能干翻一辆车
You stop a car with this.
我想要点更安静点的东西
I was thinking something more silent.
比如棍棒
Like a club.
或者锐器什么的
And sharp.
有  有
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
我喜欢你的想法  安静又高效  对吧
Yeah, I like how you think. Silent but effective. Huh?
很好
Okay.
瞧瞧这个
Check this out.
我自己做的
Made it myself.
我叫它僵尸重击
I call it "The Z Whacker."
从一根铝棒开始
You start with an aluminum bat
亲手改装它
then customize it for the task at hand.
真轻
Wow. It's light.
证实  这些尖钉是我亲手用啤酒瓶磨出来的
Yeah, the spikes are hand cast from beer cans.
它足够长  能够击碎僵尸的大脑
So they're long enough that they kill the brain
还能顺利地抽出来
but you can still pull it out.
因为没有什么比武器卡在僵尸的脑子里更糟糕了
Cuz nothing is worse than getting your pike stuck into a z's skull.
那样的话你就必须得把僵尸拖到地上
Cuz then you got to drag them down to the ground.
用脚踩住它们的胸膛
You got to put your foot on their chest.
还要使劲把武器抽出来
Then you got to yank the thing out.
完成之前你早就没命了
And by then you're dead.
你懂我的意思吧
You know what I mean?
这种事的确很烦人
Sure do hate that.
我们以物易物怎么样
How about a straight across trade?
一打阿司匹林
A dozen of these aspirin
换一打223号枪用的弹药
for a dozen of these reloaded .223's.
阿司匹林又不能杀僵尸
You can't kill a zombie with aspirin.
那发烧也不能用子弹降温啊
Well you can't kill a fever with a bullet
而且他们都不生产阿司匹林了
and they ain't making any more aspirin.
改成一打奥施康定[止痛药]就成交
Make it a dozen oxycontin and you got a deal.
那我得先吃一打奥施康定
I'd have to take a dozen oxycontin
才能来做这个交易
before I'd make that deal.
冰毒怎么样
How 'bout some meth?
你想要冰毒吗
Huh? You want some crystal?
我自己做的
Yeah, I baked it myself.
跟你之前做的粉色冰块一样吗
That same pink ice you made before?
不要  那东西让我脑袋疼得差点炸了
No, that stuff gave me an axe to the skull headache.
别啊  这不是有阿司匹林吗
No, that's what the aspirin's for.
你那里还剩几剂吗啡
How many ampules of morphine you got left in there?
你后面
Behind you.
不错  你没事吧  差一点啊
Nice. You all right? That was a little close.
是啊  这个  这个速度很快
Yeah, that... that was a fast one.
够野蛮
Brutal.
就是说嘛
Told ya.
那不是红毛汉森吗
Hey, isn't that Red Hanson?
僵尸咬了红毛
Z's got Red?
见鬼  他是我们最好的顾客之一
Damn, he was one of our best customers
比子弹还坚强的人
tough as bullets.
我在想他兄弟们知不知道
I wonder if his brothers know.
我觉得他们知道  因为他们来了
Yeah, I think so cuz here they come.
打烊了
Closing time.
看那个大块头的行动方式
The way that big one moved
肯定是几小时前才刚变异
he must have turned just a few hours ago.
四个兄弟  近期变异
Four brothers, recently turned,
在萨特农场旁的米勒路上发现
found on Miller's Road by Sutter's Farm.
慈悲为怀  疫情爆发第三年五月十三日
Given mercy, May 13, 3 A.Z.
该走了
Time to go.
这边有一个
I got something over here.
看来是冲上来的浮尸
Looks like a floater washed up.
这边又有一个
I got another one over here.
这个看上去也死透了
This one looks dead and down too.
唐纳
Donner.
看
Look.
这得有几百个
Must be hundreds of them.
蓝天营  我是机动一号
Camp Blue Sky, this is mobile one.
蓝天  我是机动一号  完毕
Blue Sky, this is mobile one. Over.
各位  我需要你们的回应
Hey guys, I need you to get back to us.
现在是下午八点的信号检查时间
It's time for our 8 p.m. signal check.
你们还在浪费什么时间
What are you wasting time for?
你们自己说他们会没事的
You said yourself they'd be fine.
肯定发生了什么事
Look, there must be something wrong.
如果待会还是没有回应  那我们得回去
If we don't hear from them soon, we're gonna have to go back.
我不认为我会让你们这么做
I don't think I can let you do that.
如果我的人有事
If something is wrong with my people
我才不管你的什么狗屁任务
I don't give a damn about your mission.
亦或是你
Or you.
我们回去
We're going back.
听着
Look.
我很欣赏你们对朋友的忠诚  真的
I appreciate your loyalty to those folks. I do.
但你们不像我一样了解这个男人
But you don't know what I know about this man.
我们为什么要相信你的话
Why should we believe a word you say?
下车
Get out of the car.
给他们看
Show them.
让他们看看为什么你这么重要
Show them why you're so damn important.
别碰我
Get your hands off me.
让他们看看为什么牺牲了那么多好人
Show them why so many good men died
就为让你走到这里
getting you this far.
让他们看看
Show them!
发生什么事了
What happened?
这些都是僵尸咬的
Those are Zombie bites.
八个僵尸
Eight of them.
为什么他还活着
Why is he still alive?
而且还不是僵尸
And not a zombie?
被咬之前  他刚打了唯一一支
He was given the only dose of an experimental vaccine
试验阶段的疫苗
right before he was bitten.
那些半死不活的杂种咬掉了我这里的两根肋骨
Those undead bastards got two of my ribs right there.
闭嘴
Shut up.
至少你还活着
At least you're still alive.
这话我可没法跟我的人说
More than I can say for my men.
在你们面前的是唯一已知的被僵尸咬伤之后
You're looking at the only human known to have survived
还能活下来的人
being bitten by a Zombie.
他的血液里有ZN1病毒的抗体
His blood carries the antibodies for the ZN1 virus.
如果我们能把他送到加利福尼亚的实验室
If we can get him to the lab in California
他们就能用他的血造出更多抗体
they can use his blood and make more of the vaccine.
求救求救  呼叫蓝天营
Mayday. Mayday. Calling Camp Blue Sky.
我是多克  和汤姆森和卡弗一起
This is Doc. With Thompson and Carver.
你那边情况如何  完毕
What is your situation? Over.
嗨多克  怎么了
Hey, Doc. What's going on? What's going on?
加内特吗  谢天谢地你们还活着
Garnett? Thank God you're alive.
我们以为所有人都死了
We thought everyone was dead.
我不在蓝天营  发生什么事了
I'm not at Camp Blue Sky. What's happening?
电量不足了
Batteries... dying.
等等  在说一遍
Wait. Say. Again.
蓝天营被僵尸肆虐了
Blue Sky has been overrun.
整个营地被大火吞噬了
The whole place is...on fire.
有生还者吗
Survivors?
之前有猛烈的枪声  但现在停了
Well there was a ton of gunfire a while ago, but nothing since.
来吧  我们走
Come on. Let's go.
那有一辆逃生巴士
Oh... There's the escape bus.
他们救出了孩子  太好了
Oh, they got the kids out. Okay.
快点
Come on.
上车
Get in!
快点走
Go! Go! Go!
有幸存者吗
How many more?
没有
Nobody.
没有嘛
Nobody?
没有  我确定
Nobody! I'm sure!
唐娜  马里昂呢
Donna? Marion?
死了  无人幸存
No...there was no one.
都没办法对其"施以仁慈"
Not even time to show any of them mercy.
无人幸存  只有僵尸
There's nobody back there but z's.
对不起大家  我们尽力了
Sorry guys. We tried.
不能为他们做什么  只求上帝怜悯
Nothing left for them now but God's mercy.
该走了  快点
It's time to go then. Come on.
我不知道为什么要带上他们
I don't know what we brought them along for.
因为他们也是人
Uh...because they're human beings
他们有权活着
and they deserve to live.
离集结地还有多远
Hey... how much further to this rendezvous?
不远了
Just a few more clicks.
我希望有十倍的
Got some vehicles and a team of killers waiting.
汽车和杀手在那等着
Wish I had ten times that.
前面应该向左走
Should be up ahead on the left.
旧中学的地下室里有民防设施
An old high school with a civil defense shelter in the basement.
应该还剩下些补给品
Supposedly there's still some rations left there.
你最后一次联系他们是何时
When was the last time you made contact with them?
大概一个月前
About a month ago.
一个月前吗
A month ago?
那相当于两年末世一般[圣经启示录]
That's like two years Apocalypse time.
纽约沉睡谷咬痕研究所集合点
回到车上
Get back in the truck.
是他们吗
Is it them?
哈蒙德
Hammond?
是他们吗
Is it them?
是的
Yeah.
我要小便
I got to pee.
别走远
Don't go far.
别担心
Don't worry.
这人真是...
This guy.
我的后援全军覆没了
My reinforcements are dead.
我们要快速寻找幸存者和供给
We need to make a quick search for survivors and any supplies.
你
You!
拉上拉链  跟紧我
Zip it up and stay close to me.
僵尸都去哪了
Hey, where'd all the z's go?
走了  就像蝗虫一般
Movin' on, like locust.
是的  但他们会回来
Yeah, but they'll be back.
加内特和沃伦  你们查看大楼
Garnett and Warren, you clear the building.
你们三个检查车辆
And you three check the vehicles.
他们看似毫无反击之力
Looks like they never had a chance.
你听见没
You hear that?
什么
Hear what?
那里
There.
听起来像是个...  婴儿
Sounds like a...baby.
糟糕
Oh shoot.
在这里
There it is.
没关系的宝贝
Hey, it's okay sweetie.
我们带你离开着
We're gonna get you out of there.
司机怎么样
How's that driver?
死了  变异了吗
Dead. Turned?
她好像朝脑袋开了一枪
Looks like she took a blow to the skull.
爆头而死
Brain dead on impact.
来吧
There you go.
嗨  麦克
Hey, Mack.
好的  我懂
Yeah, I know.
是活生生的宝宝
Whoa. It's a real live baby.
几年来我都没见过一个
I haven't seen one of these in years.
他还哭个不停
And he won't stop crying.
我该拿他怎么办
Here. What do I do?
-放着我来  -好
-Maybe don't. -Okay.
得像拿着点燃的手榴弹那样抱他  给我吧
Hold him like he's a live grenade. Just give him to me.
我对孩子没经验
Me and babies, not so much.
她带着个孩子在这里干嘛
What was she doing out here with a baby anyway?
不清楚  看来他们是来防空洞避难
I dunno. Looks like they were headed to this shelter.
跑昏头了
They got overrun.
我们带着孩子要怎么行动
What the hell are we gonna do with a baby?
不知道  这几年来我一直事到临头才做打算
Beats me. I stopped planning two minutes ahead years ago.
小心
Heads up.
他们争先恐后个什么劲
What are they after?
还不就是那个  上吧
Only one thing. Come on.
你还好吗
You all right?
小心  她可能已经死了
Careful. She might be dead.
她没死
Well she ain't dead.
没事了  没事了  我们是好人
Hey. It's okay. Hey. It's okay. We're good people.
我们刚才救了你
We just saved you.
行了  别伤着他
Okay, don't hurt him.
抱歉  我不知道自己在哪里
Sorry. I didn't know where I was.
我肯定是睡着了
I must have fallen asleep.
睡着了
Asleep?
你在这个笼子里待了多久
How long you in this cage for?
两天
Two days.
来个人快让这孩子闭嘴
Somebody better shut that kid up
否则要招来一群僵尸了
before he attracts z's like flies.
他是个孩子  哭闹很正常  好吗
It's a baby. He makes noise, okay?
闭嘴  你  尽量哄哄他
Shut up. And you, do what you can.
关于僵尸的事他说的没错
He's right about the z's.
给
Here.
为什么会有人把你关在笼子里不管你死活
Why would somebody lock you in a cage and leave you to die?
你做过什么了
What did you do?
我什么也没做过
I didn't do anything.
我把自己锁在笼子里是为了自保
I locked myself in the cage for protection.
你有钥匙吗
You have the keys?
找不着了
I lost them.
你为什么穿成这样
Why are you dressed like that?
我用不着为自己辩白
I don't have to justify myself.
你一定要
Maybe you do!
我们本该在车队那里见人的
We were supposed to meet the men in those vehicles.
发生什么了
What happened here?
那伙人是一个礼拜前出现的
Those men showed up about a week ago.
他们遣走了学校里的人  并扎了营
They cleared out the school and set up some kind of camp.
有消息说这里储存了食物
But word got out that there was food.
防空洞里有很多
Lots of it from the bomb shelter.
但食物没能维持太久  人太多了
Yeah, it didn't take long. There was too many people.
士兵射杀了一些当地人
The soldiers shot some of the locals,
尸体招来了那群僵尸
and that brought the z's.
剩下的你也猜到了
You can guess the rest.
还在这里和她废什么话
What are we wasting time talking to her for?
把孩子给她  我们走吧
Give her the baby, and let's go.
你不能把孩子交给这姑娘就走
You can't give this girl a baby and leave.
那他们也不能跟我们走
Well they can't come with us.
听着
Listen.
我绝不会抛下孩子和她一走了之的
No way am I leaving the baby and her behind.
绝不可能
It's not gonna happen.
孩子而已
It's just a baby.
又不是要看他长大成为社会栋梁
It's not like he's gonna grow up and be a fine young man someday.
你们  都给我闭嘴
You know what, shut up!
我们会把他们带到下一个安全点
We'll take them to the next safe outpost.
天  我最恨僵持不下
God, I hate moral dilemmas.
接下来做什么  队长
Yeah what's next chief?
你还想给他开设一个学院基金吗
You wanna start a college fund for him?
伙计们  两百码开外
Puppies and kittens. 200 yards away.
有僵尸
Zombies.
行了  大伙  该行动了
All right, everybody. Time to go.
你们四个  我要你们拿来一切能找到的食物和武器
You four, i want you to grab all the food and weapons you can find.
锁到卡车里  钥匙还在里面
Load them in that truck. The keys are still inside.
我们还没谈过怎么分配任务
Hey! We haven't talked about this.
我们大可以稍后再谈
We can talk about it later.
现在我说什么你就照办
Right now you do what I tell you.
加内特
Garnett!
我们回来之前你跟孩子还有摩菲一块儿待着
You stay with the baby and Murphy until we get back.
沃伦
Warren.
你跟我去看看是否能先解决那几个倒霉鬼
You and I are gonna see if we can start up that deuce and a half.
五分钟后全体回来集合
Everybody meets back here in five.
动起来
Go!
行动
Go.
好了
All right.
你现在想怎么处理
How you want to handle this?
我们通常会带上家伙去干掉它们
We usually like taking it to 'em.
长官
Sir.
好吧  就这么办
All right. Let's do this.
悄悄的
Silent.
先生  注意孩子
Hey, mister! Baby.
孩子终于闭嘴了
The kid finally shut up.
你躲开
Get away from there.
躲开
你干嘛这样
What the hell did you do that for?
摩菲
Murphy.
过来
Get over here.
快点
Go.
你还好吗
You okay?
我挺好的
Yeah, I'm great.
孩子呢
Baby?
他很虚弱  但还撑着呢
He's weak, but he's hanging in there.
给
Here.
谢谢
Thanks.
天啊
Oh God.
杀了他
Kill it.
我不行
I can't.
我做不到
I can't do it.
你做得到
Yes, you can.
不  你来
No. You do it.
不  我可不想  你必须干掉他
No, I don't want to do it. You got to kill it.
你们在等什么
What's the holdup?
孩子呢
Where's the baby?
尸变了
Turned.
好意外  好意外
Surprise. Surprise.
放开他
Let him go.
否则我让你也变成僵尸
Or I will send you to walk among the dead.
上车吧
Let's get in the trucks.
我们得走了
We're moving out.
那个小孩怎么办
What about the... the baby thing?
我们不能就这么走了
We can't leave it like that.
是啊  她说得对
Yeah, she's right.
虽然他已经尸变了
Even if it is turned.
要杀他真让人难过
It sounds so sad.
一点也不难过  他是僵尸
It's not sad. It's a zombie.
阿门  兄弟  快离开这吧
Amen brother. Let's go.
我们不能就这么走了
We can't leave it like that.
我来动手
I'll do it.
还是我来吧
我要你恢复状态
I need you to pull it together.
两分钟
Two minutes.
准备好动身
Be ready to go.
过来  宝宝
Here baby.
过来  小宝宝
Here baby-baby.
到爸爸这来
Come to papa.
如果我们要抛下他们
If we wanted to ditch these two
上车逃跑
take the truck and run
现在正是时候
now would be the time.
我就那么一说
Just sayin'.
我看到你的小贱屁股了
Oh I see your little bitch-ass.
知道吗  如果那时丢下孩子走了
You know, non of these would happen
这一切就都不会发生了
if you'd just left that damn baby.
我可没让哈蒙德把自己送给孩子吃掉
I didn't tell Hammond to go get eaten by a baby.
现在别再想那些了
Never mind that now.
我们得制定个计划
We need a plan.
我的计划就是  我要开着这辆卡车
My plan is I'm taking this truck
忘记什么疫苗啊  实验室啊
and I am forgetting about vaccines and labs
还有所有你们这些人
and all of you.
我从一开始就不想掺合这件事
I wanted off this train from day one,
现在我的机会来了
and now's my chance.
等等  等等  你不能就这么一走了之
Wait-wait-wait. You can't just go.
去加州的事怎么办  疫苗怎么办
What about California? What about the vaccine?
万一是真的呢  万一是个机会呢
What if it's real? What if there's a chance?
如果是你  会怎么样
And what if it's you?
艾迪
Addy.
我们怎么知道那不是胡说八道呢
How do we know this isn't all just bullshit?
所有人都没有任何头绪
How does anybody know anything anymore?
三角洲X光小队
Delta-Xray-Delta.
什么东西
What the hell is that?
三角洲X光小队  回话
Delta-Xray-Delta. Come in.
三角洲X光小队  这里是极光
Delta-Xray-Delta. This is Northern Light.
咬痕研究所  听到了吗
Operation Bitmark. Do you copy?
三角洲X光小队
Delta-Xray-Delta.
是哈蒙德的对讲机
It's Hammond's radio.
三角洲X光小队  这里是北极光阵地
Delta-Xray-Delta. This is Northern Light.
有人在么
Hello?
三角洲X光小队  我听到了
I copy you Delta-Xray!
这里  这里是北极光阵地
This is...this is Northern Light.
你是谁
Who am I speaking to?
艾迪生·卡弗
Addison Carver.
好的  我要跟哈蒙德中尉讲话
Okay. I need to speak to Lieutenant Hammond.
哈蒙德已经死了
Hammond's dead.
抱  抱歉
I'm...I'm...I'm sorry.
我没听清三角洲X光小队
I...I didn't copy that, Delta-Xray.
你刚才说哈蒙德死了吗
Did you say that Hammond is dead?
是的
Yes.
包裹还安全吗
Is the package safe?
包裹  什么包裹
Package? What...what package?
他是谁
Who is this?
听着  我要求跟你们的头儿讲话
Listen. I need to speak to whoever's in charge.
对方是谁
Who is it?
他们不说
They won't say.
他们要求跟头儿讲话
They want to know who's in charge.
你是头儿
You are.
我是国民警卫队的加内特中士你是谁
This is Sergeant Garnett of the National Guard. Who is this?
加内特中士
Sergeant Garnett.
哈蒙德中尉在转移一位
Lieutenant Hammond was transporting a civilian
名叫摩菲的市民到加利福尼亚
named Murphy to California.
他还活着吗
Is he alive?
是的  他还活着
Yes. He's still alive.
很好  很好
Good. Good.
你知道咬痕研究所吗
Are...are you aware of Operation Bitemark?
你是指位于加利福尼亚的实验室吗
Do you mean the lab in California?
是的  是的  听我说
Yes! Yes! Listen to me!
你必须要将摩菲送往加利福尼亚
It is imperative that you get Murphy to California.
再重复一遍
I repeat.
你必须保证将摩菲活着送到加利福尼亚
It is imperative that you get Murphy alive to California.
收到了吗
Do you copy?
但是  我们不知道
But we don't know...
你是谁
Who are you?
加内特
Garnett?
加内特  你听到了吗
Garnett, do you copy?
加内特
Garnett!
这玩意挂了
It's dead.
该死
Damn it!
所以
So?
So...
我们要将卧底先生送往加利福尼亚
It looks like we're taking Mr. Congeniality here to California.
谁下的令
Says who?
我
Says me.
你好啊
Hey there.
你就是那位救我一命的神枪手  是不是
You're that sharp shooter that saved my ass, aren't you?
老兄
Oh man.
我想跟你说声谢谢
I want to thank you.
需要捎你一程吗
Do you need a ride?
我知道你们在那  我能看到你们
I know you're out there. I can see you.
逃跑  躲藏  杀戮  求生
Running. Hiding. Killing. Surviving.
我全都看见了
I've seen it all.
就像在玩《虐杀丧尸》
Season tickets to the Zompocalypse.
我要告诉你们
And I got to tell you people,
尽管我们这一战有所损失
we've been getting our asses kicked.
但是  从今天开始事情将有所改观
Well today's the day that all that changes.
是的  我将不再袖手旁观
That's right. I'm not just watching anymore.
是时候给僵尸们致命一击了
It's time to kick some zombie ass.
你们现在收听到的是由宽频  低频
This is Citizen Z broadcasting
甚高频  超高频  天网直播的市民Z广播
live via broadband, low band, vhf, uhf, skynet.
如果你们接收到了信号  你们就能找到我
If you can get a signal, then you can find me
感谢我们的国家安全局合作伙伴
thanks to our friends at the NSA.
现在我需要收到你们任何人的回应
Now all I need is somebody, anybody, everybody to get back to me
就像开始任务时那样  只要你们还活着
cuz that's how it starts. If you're still alive,
你们可能就是某些...
you're probably some kind of...
可能天生就是某些捣蛋鬼
some kind of genetically predisposed badass.
我们现在需要的
And all we got to do is
就是团结在一起绝不给僵尸们机会
get organized and the zombies don't stand a chance.
现在我在据你们三千英里的家乡
Now here's a little something for all of you out there
为你们送上祝福
with 3,000 miles of bad road between you and home.
希望你们能听到
I hope you can hear it.